<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>XDR on Izhar&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/xdr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in XDR on Izhar&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 17:59:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/xdr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unified XDR Handbook Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/xdrhandbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 17:59:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/xdrhandbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-and-context&#34;&gt;Introduction and Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme of the book and the concepts are explained by having a target of enhancing security and digital transformation. High Tech Rapid Solutions has a staff of over 60k. The company is trying to modernize their security operations due to COVID and having their employees to work remotely instead of traditional offices. They now require a new security monitoring strategy to address their security needs. The company has a SOC but they manage it themselves&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction-and-context">Introduction and Context</h2>
<p>The theme of the book and the concepts are explained by having a target of enhancing security and digital transformation. High Tech Rapid Solutions has a staff of over 60k. The company is trying to modernize their security operations due to COVID and having their employees to work remotely instead of traditional offices. They now require a new security monitoring strategy to address their security needs. The company has a SOC but they manage it themselves</p>
<h4 id="current-environment">Current Environment</h4>
<ol>
<li>Multi cloud leveraging both Azure and AWS for infra needs</li>
<li>Hybrid cloud having both on prem and cloud resources in order to maximize their compliance, while capitalizing on scalability and cost effectiveness</li>
<li>Hybrid Identity architecture</li>
<li>Entra ID to collaborate with external partners B2B collaboration with cross tenant capabilities</li>
<li>Devices consists of 80% Windows and 20% mac, along with Android and iOS</li>
<li>Majority of servers are windows based and the rest are linux</li>
<li>Lagacy applications onprem while modern apps on cloud native technologies</li>
<li>An IoT and OT environment to optimize operations. The main challenge it lacks is the lack of security monitoring and visibility</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="security-challenges">Security Challenges</h3>
<ul>
<li>Isolated products result in lack of visibility</li>
<li>Lack of centralized monitoring and analytics</li>
<li>Lack of a unified platform that impacts the agility of the incident response process. They use a legacy SIEM and are keen to move to a modern SIEM with a cloud based solution</li>
<li>Regulatory Compliances in terms of data protection, access controls and security audits</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="management-concerns">Management Concerns</h3>
<ul>
<li>Lack of visibility and control of IoT/OT environment</li>
<li>Lack of visibility on internet exposed digital assets</li>
<li>Lack of a threat intelligence data feed</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="challenges-emphasized-by-the-security-team">Challenges emphasized by the Security team</h3>
<ul>
<li>Suspicious activity and confidential emails getting leaked</li>
<li>Struggling to gain visibility on vulnerabilities of the incidents</li>
<li>Limited resources that leads to incident response challenges</li>
<li>Long hours fulfilling management ad hoc reporting needs</li>
<li>Absence of a defined process and a dedicated vulnerability management team</li>
<li>Unauthorised users accessing HR apps and services</li>
<li>Team needs training for the new technologies</li>
<li>Too many false positives addressing these issues took a lot of time</li>
<li>Lack of monitoring on On prem identities</li>
<li>Lack of security posture management for both on prem and cloud resources</li>
<li>Failing to identify possible attack paths to cloud resources</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="concerns-by-ciso">Concerns by CISO</h3>
<ul>
<li>Attacks on m365 collaboration workloads</li>
<li>Ransomware Attacks</li>
<li>Business Email compromise Attacks</li>
</ul>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="/images/mountain.png"
         alt="A mountain"/> <figcaption>
            <p>This is a white kitten</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
